Finding Aid for WUOM Records, 1914-1982
Bentley Historical Library, University of Michigan
- Audio Material 1930s-1970s
  - Sound Reels (10 1/2-inch")
    - U-M Ceremonies and Convocations
      - Dedication Ceremony: Institute for Social Research / George Romney; Marvin L. Niehuss; Rensis Likert March 30, 1966, [R188B] (Box 24)
        (broadcast Lecture Hour July 16, 1966)
      - Dedication Ceremony: Mental Health Research Institute January 30, 1960, 2 reels; [R189B-R190B] (Box 24)
      - Dedication Ceremony: School of Music; Honorary degree presentation / Michigan Band; [____] Wallace; Harlan H. Hatcher; Aline Saarinen; Aaron Copland; Leonard Bernstein; Earl V. Moore; Michigan Men's Glee Club September 19, 1964, [R191B] (Box 24)
      - Freshman Orientation Convocation / Harlan H. Hatcher August 29, 1966, [R192B] (Box 24)
      - Honorary Degree Convocation: James A. McDivitts and Edward H. White; Dedication Ceremony: Space Research Laboratory June 15, 1965, [R193B] (Box 24)
      - Memorial Service: Martin Luther King / Allan F. Smith; Albert Wheeler; Samuel Jones; Emmett Green; William Haber; Opal Bailey; Magit [sic] Downs April 5, 1968, [R194B] (Box 24)
    - U-M Conferences and Lectures
      - Alumni University
        - Speech ("Today's Faculty") / Roger W. Heyns, recorded April 29, 1965, [R195B] (Box 24)
          (broadcast Lecture Hour August 5, 1965)
      - Anti-War Rally (various local sponsors)
        - Informal speeches / Dave Dellinger, et al., recorded October 10, 1972, [R196B] (Box 24)
      - Creative Arts Festival
        - "The Aesthetic Vacuum of Our Age" [speech] / Ayn Rand, recorded May 14, 1961 broadcast Lecture Hour, July 8, 1961, [R197B] (Box 24)
        - [Lecture and poetry reading] / John Ciardi, recorded May 10, 1961, [R198B] (Box 25)
          (broadcast Lecture Hour June 26, 1961)
        - [Poetry reading / Robert Penn Warren, recorded March 18, 1965, [R199B] (Box 25)
          (broadcast Lecture Hour September 2, 1965)
        - [Poetry reading] / Robert Lowell, recorded March 20, 1965, [R200B] (Box 25)
          (broadcast Lecture Hour September 9, 1965)
        - [Poetry reading] / W. D. Snodgrass--[recorded] March 20, 1966, 15 ips; [R201B] (Box 25)
      - Department of Classical Studies
        - Reading [original translation of Aeschylus's "Agamemnon") / Robert Lowell, recorded January 17, 1966, [R202B] (Box 25)
          (broadcast Lecture Hour May 7, 1966)
      - Department of English
        - Lecture and poetry reading / Robert Creely; introduced by Donald Hall. November 9, 1964, [R203B] (Box 25)
        - [Poetry reading] / James Wright; introduced by Donald Hall, recorded October 27, 1958, [R204B] (Box 25)
          (broadcast Lecture Hour [1958])
        - [Poetry reading] / Denise Levertov--recorded April 30, 1962 broadcast Lecture Hour, August 30, 1962, [R205B] (Box 25)
        - [Poetry reading] / Robert Bly; introduced by Donald Hall, recorded November 20, 1962, [R206B] (Box 25)
          (broadcast Lecture Hour January 16, 1963)
        - [Poetry reading] / John Hollander--recorded December 4, 1962, [R207B] (Box 25)
          (broadcast Lecture Hour February 28, 1963)
        - [Poetry reading] / John Woods; introduced by Mark Spilka, recorded February 19, 1963, [R208B] (Box 25)
          (broadcast Lecture Hour April 20, 1963)
        - [Poetry reading] / Robert Bly, recorded November 12, 1963, [R209B] (Box 25)
          (broadcast Lecture Hour January 6, 1964)
        - "Reaching the Unreached: English in Every Classroom" [speech] / Daniel Fader--recorded August 2, 1965 [part of Toward the Better Teaching of High School English Conference], broadcast Lecture Hour, August 30, 1965, [R210B] (Box 25)
        - Symposium on the Contemporary English Novel [panel discussion] / Marvin Felheim; James Gindin; Donald Hall, recorded March 13, 1959, [R211B] (Box 25)
        - "Toys in the Attic" [lecture and reading] / Lillian Hellman, recorded April 6, 1960 broadcast [Lecture Hour] August 16, 1960, [R212B] (Box 25)
      - Draft Teach-In (March 19, 1968)
        - "The Draft and the University" [panel discussion] / James Lafferty; Paul Rupert; James Jones; William Sloan Coffin; introduced by William Gamson, recorded March 19, 1968, [R213B] (Box 26)
          (broadcast Lecture Hour June 1, 1968)
        - ["The Rights and Responsibilities of Dissent in a Free Society"] [panel discussion / Herbert [Kelman]; Terry Sandalow; Spencer Parsons; Bob Harris; William Sloane Coffin, recorded March 19, 1968, [R214B] (Box 26)
      - Ecumenical Campus Center/First Presbyterian Church. Church and Society Committee
        - "Campus Unrest" [panel discussion] / Paul R. Dotson; Robben W. Fleming; Gardner Ackley; Joseph N. Payne; Gordon J. Van Wylen; Stephen J. Tonsor; Terence N. Tice; Gilbert E. Bursley, recorded July 7, 1970, [R215B] (Box 26)
          (excerpts broadcast Commentary July 9, 16, 23, 30, 1970)
      - Esquire Symposium (Department of English Annual Writer's Conference)
        - "The Role of the Writer in America") [speech and panel discussion] / Nelson Algren; Gore Vidal; William Styron; Vance Bourjaily; introduced by Allen Seager, recorded October 27-28, 1961, 3 reels; [R216B-R218B] (Box 26)
          (broadcast Lecture Hour February 7-8, 1962)
      - [Howe Symposium]
        - "Radical Resistance: Success or Suicide?" [panel discussion] / Barry Bluestone; Tom Maher; Irving Howe; John Bishop, recorded January 19, 1968, [R219B] (Box 26)
          (broadcast Lecture Hour March 16, 1968)
      - Hopwood Ceremonies
        - Lectures
          - Malcolm Cowley; introduced by Arno Bader 1957, [R220B] (Box 26)
            (broadcast May 1957)
          - John Ciardi ("The Silences of the Poem"); introduced by Arno Bader 1958, [R221B] (Box 26)
            (broadcast Lecture Hour June 14, 1958)
          - Howard Nemerov ("The Swaying Form: A Problem in Poetry); introduced by Allen Seager 1959, [R222B] (Box 26)
            (broadcast Lecture Hour [1959])
          - Saul Bellow 1961, [R223B] (Box 26)
            (broadcast Lecture Hour June 20, 1961)
          - Mark Schorer; introduced by Arno Bader 1962, [R224B] (Box 26)
            (rebroadcast Lecture Hour August 23, 1962)
          - Arthur Miller ("Recognition"); introduced by Arno Bader 1963, [R225B] (Box 26)
            (broadcast Lecture Hour June 5, 1963 rebroadcast Lecture Hour December 2, 1963)
          - Alfred Kazin ("Autobiography As Narrative"); introduced by Arno Bader 1964, [R226B] (Box 26)
            (broadcast Lecture Hour May 9, 1964)
          - Donald Davie ("Sincerity and Poetry"); introduced by Arno Bader 1965, [R227B] (Box 26)
          - Stephen Spender 1982, [R228B] (Box 26)
            (broadcast July 28, [1982])
        - Readings
          - Kenneth Rexroth with Kyoto, recorded January 17, 1979, [R229B] (Box 26)
          - John Ciardi, et al., recorded April 10, 1981, 2 reels; [R230B-R231B] (Box 27)
      - Institute for Continuing Legal Education
        - Student Protest and the Law Conference. May 16-17, 1969, 1 reel of 7 retained (Box 27)
        - Welcome Address / Robben W. Fleming; "Dimensions of Legitimate Student Dissent" [panel discussion] / Paul D. Carrington, moderator; Richard L. Cates; Marvin L. Niehuss; Robert N. Knause, [R232B] (Box 27)
      - Michigan Union Cultural Affairs Committee
        - [Lecture and poetry reading] / Robert Frost; introduced by Donald Hall, recorded April 2, 1962, [R233B] (Box 27)
          (broadcast Lecture Hour May 2, 1962, rebroadcast December 24, 1971)
      - New Mobilization Committee; Friends of the White Panthers
        - [Talk] / Jane Fonda, recorded December 1, 1970 [broadcast February 9, 1971] Audition copy available in Box 16., [R234B] (Box 27)
      - Office of Religious Affairs
        - "Symbol and Myth: The Language of Religion" [lecture] / Paul Tillich, recorded November 13, 1960, [R235B] (Box 27)
          (, broadcast Lecture Hour January 21, 1961, rebroadcast Lecture Hour June 19, 1961)
        - "An Understanding of Black Power" [speech] / Stokley Carmichael, recorded September 27, [R236B] (Box 27)
          (1966 Co-sponsored by ORA, Union-League Activities Committee, and Friends of Student Non-violent Coordinating Committee (SNCC))
      - Repression Teach-In (sponsor: Ann Arbor Committee on Repression)
        - [Speeches] / Jerry Rubin; Arthur Kinoy; Edward Crowther; et al., recorded January 30, 1970, 3 reels; [R237B-R239B] (Box 27)
      - Teach-In on the Environment (sponsors: ENACT; New Mobilization Committee)
        - "Citizen Action" [speech] / Ralph Nader--recorded March 14, 1970 broadcast Lecture Hour, May 16, 1970, [R240B] (Box 27)
        - [War and the Environment] [panel discussion] / Kenneth Boulding; Anatol Rapoport; Douglas Fulton; Irwin Goldstein; David Gordon, broadcast Lecture Hour, May 23, 1970, [R241B] (Box 27)
      - Unidentified Sponsorship
        - [Poetry reading] / Katherine Anne Porter, recorded March 4, 1954, [R242B] (Box 27)
        - [Poetry reading] / G.B. Harrison, recorded April 29, 1954, [R243B] (Box 27)
        - [Poetry reading] / Bennett Weaver--recorded March 24, 1955, [R244B] (Box 27)
        - [Poetry reading] / e.e. cummings, recorded March 20, 1957, [R245B] (Box 27)
        - [Poetry reading] / Robert Graves; introduced by Norman Nelson, recorded February 12, 1958, [R246B] (Box 28)
        - [Poetry reading] / e.e. cummings; introduced by Frank Cople May 9, 1960, [R247B] (Box 28)
        - [Poetry reading] / Louis Simpson, recorded March 16, 1966, [R248B] (Box 28)
        - [Poetry reading] / Lemuel Johnson, recorded February 21, 1978, [R249B] (Box 28)
        - [Poetry reading] / Joseph Brodsky, recorded March 15, 1979, 2 reels; [R250B-R251B] (Box 28)
        - [Speech] / Malcolm X., recorded October 21, 1963 [October 22?], [R252B] (Box 28)
      - University Activities Center (UAC)
        - "Exploration of the Moods of Dissent: A Dialogue with the President" [forum] / Robben W. Fleming, et al., recorded March 18, 1968, 2 reels; [R253B-R254B] (Box 28)
        - "Poets on the War in Vietnam" [Poetry Read-In] / Robert Bly; Will Gear; W.D. Snodgrass; John Woods; Tim Reynolds; Jerry Badanes; Donald Hall; Galway Kinnell, recorded October 2-3, 1966, 2 reels; [R255B-R256B] (Box 28)
        - "The Recent Past and the Immediate Future" [speech and question/answer session]) / Benjamin Spock, recorded February 2, 1969, [R257B] (Box 28)
          (Topic: war resistance and pacifism; broadcast Lecture Hour April 26, 1969)
      - University of Michigan Afro-American Retreat
        - [Scholarship for Long-term Change] [panel discussion] / Ivanhoe Donaldson; Ronald Harris; Lonnie Peek; Louis Lomax May 6, 1969, [R258B] (Box 28)
      - University of Michigan Centennial of Lincoln's Emancipation Proclamation
        - [Lecture and poetry reading] / Langston Hughes--recorded January 8, 1963 broadcast Lecture Hour, March 9, 1963, [R259B] (Box 28)
      - University of Michigan Senate
        - Meeting, recorded February 15, 1982, [R260B] (Box 29)
          (Vice President Frye presents the Five-Year Plan)
        - [Report on Black Action Movement and actions taken in response to BAM demands] / Robben W. Fleming, recorded April 13, 1970, [R261B] (Box 29)
          (broadcast Lecture Hour April 13, 1970 (Incomplete)
      - Vietnam Teach-In
        (See also: Sub-series Sound Reels (7-inch"))
        - [Personal Views Concerning Vietnam War] [speech] Robben W. Fleming, recorded September 19, 1969, October 15, 1969, [R262B] (Box 29)
          (broadcast Special of the Week September 20, 1969 (Incomplete))
        - [Response to Fleming; Report on visit to Hanoi] [speech] / Rennie Davis, recorded September 19, 1969, October 15, 1969, [R263B] (Box 29)
      - War Moratorium (sponsor: New Mobilization to End the War)
        - [Rally at Michigan Stadium [live broadcast] [speech] / Rennie Davis, recorded September 19, 1969, October 15, 1969, [R264B] (Box 29)
          (Includes excerpts from speeches made at other Moratorium sessions)
        - [Speech] / Allen Ginsburg, recorded October 15, 1969, [R265B] (Box 29)
    - U-M History
      - History Archives [oral history interviews] original recording 1965-1966, 7 reels; 3 3/4 ips
        ([see participant list below] Summaries of interviews available.)
        - Reel #1: Leo Sharfman; Charles Sink; Ralph Sawyer; Stanley Dodge, [R266B] (Box 29)
        - Reel #2: George Carrothers; Harrison Randall; Preston Slosson; Hazel Losh, [R267B] (Box 29)
        - Reel #3: Margaret Tracy; Henry Frieze Vaughn; Wells I. Bennett, [R268B] (Box 29)
        - Reel #4: Henry Carter Adams II; Arthur Dearth Moore; Arthur Denham, [R269B] (Box 29)
        - Reel #5: Clarence Cook Little; Samuel Dana; William Trow; Ruel Churchill, [R270B] (Box 29)
        - Reel #6: Philip Bursley; E. Blythe Stason; Roscoe Bonnisteel; Charles Kennedy, [R271B] (Box 29)
        - Reel #7: Helen Hebelar; William Paton; Arthur Furstenberg, [R272B] (Box 29)
    - U-M Sesquicentennial Celebration
      - $55 Million Dollar Campaign (Box 29)
      - Speeches (Victory Dinner) / Frederick Matthai; Gilbert Bursley; Paul Goebel; Herbert Hildebrandt; Harlan H. Hatcher; Michigan Band; Michigan Men's Glee Club December 9, 1967, 2 reels; [R273B-R274B] (Box 29)
      - University of Michigan Birthday Symposium [Alumni Weekend]
        - "The Right of Free Discussion" [panel discussion; question/answer session] / Mike Wallace; Arnold Gingrich; Arthur Miller, recorded March 2, 1967, 2 reels; [R275B-R276B] (Box 30)
      - Voices of Civilization Lecture Series October 2-6, 1967 (Major Ceremony IV)
        - "The American Racial Question" [lecture] / Gunnar Myrdal, recorded October 2, 1967, [R277B] (Box 30)
          (broadcast Lecture Hour December 23, 1967)
        - "The Origins of Life" [lecture] / Harold Urey, recorded October 3, 1967, [R278B] (Box 30)
          (broadcast Lecture Hour December 9, 1967)
        - "The Formations of the Notions of Speed and Time" [lecture] / Jean Piaget October 3, 1967, [R279B] (Box 30)
          (In French & English)
        - "The American Racial Question" [dialogue] / Gunnar Myrdal; Ralph Ellison--recorded October 4, 1967, 2 reels; [R280B-R281B] (Box 30)
        - "Europe and Asia in American Foreign Policy" [symposium] / Dean Acheson; Edwin Reischauer, recorded October 4, 1967, [R282B] (Box 30)
          (broadcast Commentary October 5, 1967, broadcast Lecture Hour December 16, 1967)
        - "The Birth of an Opera" [lecture] / Luigi Dallapiccola, recorded October 4, 1967, [R283B] (Box 30)
          (broadcast Lecture Hour December 29, 1967)
        - "Memory" [lecture] / Jean Piaget, recorded October 5, 1967, [R284B] (Box 30)
        - [Lecture] / [____] Kurylovicz, recorded October 5, 1967, [R285B] (Box 30)
        - "Science and Humanism" [lecture] / Michael DeBakey, recorded October 5, 1967, [R286B] (Box 30)
          (broadcast Lecture Hour December 30, 1967)
        - "Cities and Their Plight" [lecture] / Harlan H. Hatcher, recorded October 6, 1967, [R287B] (Box 30)
          ([Voices of Civilization Convocation], broadcast Commentary December 12, 1967)
    - State and Local History and Events
      - Ann Arbor Fair Housing Ordinance (Proposed): Public Hearing / Ann Arbor Common Council; Fred Hindley, announcer--broadcast March 19, 1963, 2 reels; [R288B-R289B] (Box 30)
  - Sound Discs
    - WUOM: Original Productions
      - Euripides' Orestes: A new dramatic version by the University of Michigan translator; Don Gillis, composer; Orien Dalley, conductor; Jerry Sandler, director, First radio performance, 1960, 2 phonograph records; 12 in., 33 1/3 rpm; [D1] (Box 31)
    - WUOM: Program Series
      - "Festival of Song" 1959/60-1970/71, 7 phonograph records; 12 in., 33 1/3 rpm; [D2-D8]
        - Theme Music for Down Story Book Lane, 1 phonograph records; 12 in., 33 1/3 rpm; [D9] (Box 31)
          (test pressing, recorded December 30, 1958)
    - University of Michigan: Ceremonies and Convocations
      - [Acceptance Speech, Baird Carillon Dedication] / Charles Baird; [Nationally broadcast greetings to University of Michigan Alumni Clubs / T. Hawley Tapping, recorded 1937, 1 phonograph records; aluminum acetate; 10 in., 78 rpm; [D10] (Box 31)
      - [Address] to Rochester [Alumni Club] / T. Hawley Tapping; [Comments on University of Michigan 100th Anniversary / Arthur L. Cross, recorded 1937, 1 phonograph records; aluminum acetate; 10 in., 78 rpm); [D11] (Box 31)
      - [Addresses for] 110th Birthday Party of University of Michigan / Alexander G. Ruthven, Clair Hughes, recorded January 16, 1947, 1 phonograph records; aluminum acetate, inside start; 12 in., 33 1/3 rpm; [D12] (Box 31)
        (broadcast March 18, 1947)
      - [Comments on University of Michigan 100th Anniversary] / Arthur L. Cross; To the Dallas Alumni January 20, 1938 / T. Hawley Tapping, recorded 1938, 1 phonograph records; aluminum acetate; 8 in., 33 1/3 rpm; [D13] (Box 31)
        (Cross recording is in poor condition)
      - [Comments re: "Varsity" and the 1937 Michigan football team] / Fielding H. Yost; Harry Kipke; Michigan Band, 1 phonograph records sides 1 and 3; aluminum acetate; 12 in., 78 rpm; [D14] (Box 31)
      - Football Preview 1953 / Bill Fleming, Fritz Crisler, et al., 2 phonograph records; 12 in., 33 1/3 rpm; [D15] (Box 31)
      - Rose Bowl Greetings / Fritz Crisler; 111th Anniversary greetings / Alexander G. Ruthven, [T. Hawley] Tapping, recorded 1948, 1 phonograph records; aluminum acetate; 10 in. 33 1/3 rpm; [D16] (Box 31)
- Printed Material
  Printed Materials are divided into two series: Unit Publications and Sub-Unit Publications. The Unit Publications series includes annual reports from 1933-1985, articles about the radio station, brochures, an almost complete run of programming schedules, and specific program publications. The specific program publications include brochures, scores, programs, manuals, newsletters, schedules, and transcripts of original programming from WUOM such as the Festival of Song, Michigan Radio Classroom, Michigan University of the Air, Radio Music Courses, and the WUOM Radio Classroom. The Sub-Unit Publications series includes brochures and a manual from the Package Program Service. The Tape Transcription Service created a list of the Programs Produced by WUOM for Rebroadcasts to Schools in Northern Michigan.
  - Unit Publications
    - Annual and Miscellaneous Reports
      - 1933-1947, 2 volumes (Box 32)
      - 25th Annual Report of the University Broadcasting Service, 1950 (Box 32)
      - 1951-1985, 4 folders (Box 32)
    - Articles 1926-1965 (Box 32)
    - Brochures
      - Undated 1944-1989 (Box 32)
      - Long Range Plan for Radio Station WUOM, 1987-1990, 1987 (Box 32)
      - Soundprints, [1987] (Box 32)
      - Ten Years of Educational Broadcasting, 1948-1958, [1958] (Box 32)
    - Flyers, [1950] (Box 32)
    - Programs 1967-1992 (Box 32)
    - Newsleters
      - On the Air, 1997-1999 (Box 32)
      - Michigan radio Quarterly, 2001-2002 (Box 32)
      - Broadcasting Newsletter, 1944 (Box 32)
      - Off Mike, 2002-2004 (Box 32)
    - Prospectus
      - WUOM of the University of Michigan, by Collins Radio Company, Cedar Rapids, Iowa, [1949 ?] (Box 32)
    - Reports
      - Monthly 1937-1947 (Box 32)
      - A Long Range Plan (Box 32)
    - Schedules
      - Announcement of Radio Programs, Undated, 1935-1944, 1976 (Box 32)
      - On the Air: for the Friends of Michigan Radio, 1997- (Box 32)
      - Program Schedules, 1947-1962, 15 folders (Box 32)
      - Program Guide, 1963-1978, 16 folders (Box 32)
      - Program Guide, 1979-1983, 5 folders (Box 33)
      - Soundprints, 1983-1994, 12 folders (Box 33)
      - Weekly Schedules Undated, 1937-1938 (Box 33)
    - Specific Program Series Publications
      - Class in Stage and Radio Diction
        - Schedule 1937-1938 (Box 34)
      - Education for the Veteran
        - Transcripts 1946 (Box 34)
      - Festival of Song
        - Brochures Undated (Box 34)
        - Programs
          - The Spring Songfest, 1966-1970 (Box 34)
        - Scores
          - Piano Accompaniment, 1966-1970 (Box 34)
          - Student Song Books, 1950-1970, 2 folders (Box 34)
      - The Great Lakes
        - Manuals
          - Broadcast Handbook for Teachers' Use, 1947 (Box 34)
      - Hobbying at the Piano
        - Scores 1951 (Box 34)
        - Michigan, My Michigan, 1940-1941 (Box 34)
          (List of Suggested Topics)
      - Michigan Night
        - Transcripts
          - "Michigan Night" Radio Speeches, 1928-1933 (Box 34)
      - Michigan Radio Classroom
        - Manuals
          - Teachers' Manuals, 1953-1970, 7 folders (Box 34)
        - Newsletters
          - The Michigan Radio Classroom News, 1955 (Box 34)
        - Schedules 1951 (Box 34)
        - Specific Programs
          - Modern Painting: A Series of Twelve Radio Discussions on Modern Painters and Their Work
            - Schedules 1947 (Box 34)
            - Transcripts 1947 (Box 34)
      - Michigan University of the Air
        - Manuals
          - Course in the Playing of All Band Instruments, Undated, 1931-1932 (Box 34)
          - Five-week Course in the Playing of All Band Instruments, 1931 (Box 34)
          - A Radio Course for Stringed Instruments: Violin, Viola, Cello, String Bass, 1932 (Box 34)
          - A Radio Course in Singing for Elementary Schools, 1933 (Box 34)
          - Radio Music Course for Band Instruments (Box 34)
        - Scores 1933-1935, 2 folders (Box 34)
      - Radio Music Course for Stringed Instruments
        - Scores 1933-1951 (Box 34)
      - Radio Programs Given at the University of Michigan
        - Transcripts 1925-1945, 2 folders (Box 34)
      - WUOM Radio Classroom
        - Manuals 1952 (Box 34)
  - Sub-Unit Publications
    - Package Program Service
      - Brochures 1956
        - Manuals Package Program Service to Michigan Radio Stations From Station WUOM, 1961 (Box 34)
    - Tape Transcription Service
      - Programs Produced by WUOM for Rebroadcasts to Schools in Northern Michigan, 1951 (Box 34)